

Curriculum Vitae for Max Akira Endo Kokubun

Personal information

Address: Waldemars Hage 3 E-mail: max@xal.no

0175 Oslo Phone: +47 922 98 573

Born: 24.01.1986 Nationality: Brazilian

Summary

In essence, I am a problem-solver who relies on my extense scientific knowledge and experience in academia. I have a PhD in Aerospace Engineering, from the National Institute for Space Research (INPE, 2014) and before joining Expert Analytics I held two postdoctoral positions, one in Applied Mathematics, at the National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IMPA, 2014-2016), and one in Chemistry/Applied Mathematics, at the University of Bergen (UiB, 2016-2019). My role in these projects was to develop mathematical models, and its associated numerical solvers, describing experimentally-obtained results. Thus, I have an expertise in understanding real-world problems and translating them into a mathematical framework. I worked in close collaboration with researchers from different backgrounds (physicists, engineers, mathematicians, experimentalist chemists, etc) and international institutions (Norway, Brazil, USA, Netherlands, Sweden, Belgium, UK). Therefore, I have excellent communication skills and can easily connect with both technical and non-technical audiences.

Technical skills

Frameworks Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Pandas, scikit-learn

Languages Matlab, Python, Fortran, Octave

Tools openFOAM, COMSOL, Mathematica, FEniCS, gmsh, Latex

Education

2011 - 2014 PhD in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Rese-

arch, Brazil. "Theoretical Study of Diffusion Flames Originated from the Burning of Heavy Liquid Fuels in Low Porosity Media (In-Situ

Combustion)"

2009 - 2011	Master in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Re-
	search, Brazil. "Analytical Analysis of Liquid Fuel Combustion Estab-
	lished in a Low-Porosity Medium"
2004 - 2008	Bachelor in Physics. Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.

Professional experience

2013 - 2014	Visiting Scholar. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA
2014 - 2016	Postdoctoral Fellow. National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathe-
	matics, Brazil
2016 - 2019	Postdoctoral Fellow. University of Bergen, Norway
2020	Consultant. Expert Analytics, Norway

Languages

English	Fluent
Norwegian	Good
Portuguese	Native
Spanish	Good

Personal skills

I have a facility in understanding complex problems in an organized
matter, breaking it down into smaler, easier to understand pieces.
I am considered an excellent communicator, specifically regarding sim-
plifying very technical topics to the broader audience.
I like solving real-world problems by analysing them through my scien-
tific background.
I enjoy being part of a team when solving problems. My experience in
research was always guided by collaborative work, absorbing knowledge
from more experienced researchers and guiding younger researchers.

Some interests and hobbies

Personal	Traveling, Hiking, Sports (football, swimming, rollerblading, tennis),
	Music
Scientific	Fluid Mechanics, Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD), Porous
	media, Enhanced Oil Recovery, Machine Learning, Data Science